focus
innovate enable icici lombard and cnbc
tv 18 present
india risk management awards
[Music]
in a constantly evolving and digitally
connected world
new business threats erupt every single
day
and risk management has become one of
the most rapidly changing business
functions
[Music]
as businesses get caught in the cross
hairs of geopolitics
cyber security threats extreme climate
change risk managers
have to face challenges that were never
seen before
hence they have to constantly evolve
with foresight
and act fast the sixth edition
of india risk management awards 2020
a one of its kind initiative by icici
lombard general insurance
and cnbc tv 18 recognizes organizations
that have created and adopted world
risk management practices the theme for
this year
was honoring the new age risk takers
risk is now a big
factor in the operations in fact it has
become
much more than just a factor it's
becoming
very important part of the overall
management system
and risk is not about managing anymore
it's
about taking risks in adequate quantity
but not over leveraging either the
company or the system
and this is the play we are seeing in
the risk management awards this time
very clearly in current context in the
last few years for instance
cyber threats is has emerged as a big
risk
data privacy today is emerging as a big
and climate change and sustainability is
a is a
need of the r so these are certain
things which probably a decade back
nobody
would have been talking about but we
will certainly see this as a
increasing trend
to me risk management is part of
strategy so i mean
risk management is a discipline and a
skill that you have to
build and become effective as an
organization in order to remain
competitive and strategically effective
i think the more companies build on that
capability
the more capable they will become in
terms of competing in the global economy
the eminent jury of the india risk
management awards 2020
met at the four seasons hotel in mumbai
on 20th january
this year they had a tough task at hand
to pick the winners from 15 different
categories
the distinguished five-member jury
represented
and belonged to different business
organizations and sectors
the five jury members were ramakrishnan
cfo tcs vs parthasarathy
group cfo and group cio mahindra and
mahindra
ramesh head corporate center
l t whippenke surelya cro
visa south asia rui pastors
group head of audit and risk management
reliance
industries limited i look at these
awards as
an opportunity to
reward the companies for the potential
they are offering in this space
as you know last 10 years have been an
year or era of great disruption and
in that context risk management becomes
very important and
it's in that context that what cnbc
icici lombard is trying to do is a very
very great initiative in terms of
sophistication itself there's a lot more
awareness of digital processes digital
uh you know
tools and all of that which could enable
us to actually do a lot more
in terms of being aware of the risk in
terms of mitigating
the risk and perhaps in terms of taking
to a very different level
in terms of uh operational excellence as
well
to that extent i think we are perhaps
one up on the
competition from other parts of the
globe and so on and if this continues
i'm sure
india would turn out to be a very
productive force
cnbc tv 18 joined hands with pwc
as the knowledge partner for these
awards to ensure that the entire
selection process
was completely transparent and objective
for four months pwc worked extensively
on the research and nomination process
this year there was an increase in the
number of participants
as the nominations were received from
more than 100 companies
after the completion of the nomination
process pwc
handed over the list of nominated
companies to the jury members
along with the selection criteria for
each category
each of these finalists were scrutinized
thoroughly
the entire jury process was a very
stringent one
i think that's a very robust process
that has been created
i saw a very good glimpse of that during
the
jury evaluation we saw small
big large very cutting edge
technology companies and more
physical based company all of them come
and all of them have
really evolved in terms of risk
management
it was a great eye-opener the jury
looked at various parameters
and selection criteria to pick the
winners from nominations
in fact their processes a little bit
that in fact the criteria that they laid
out
we also looked at in fact you know the
way they were able to articulate their
policies
and in some ways also connected it with
in fact their own financial outcomes the
application
isn't very important how that
application has been crafted
second is i think the our
the knowledge partner has reached out to
some of the companies to actually talk
to them as to how they have addressed
some of this
so that interactions is very important
and
also whether the applicants have given
enough examples
of how they actually deployed and how
how they are addressing this
because the proof of the
you need validation of
what is their approach and what is their
how they are
doing things so that is also important
what are the kind of practices they are
having
how good is that i compared to the other
related
and there are various factors in terms
of how
evolved it is how board is looking how
the
management is looking how operating
units are looking the key
ingredients for me have been essentially
looking at the things that
show me the outcomes so you know if
executing risk management as a
processes is one thing but have those
processes resulted in positive outcomes
for the organization both internally in
terms of delivering a strategy it's
delivering his business outcomes
can we see evidence of that i think if
we saw that it was clearly a sign that
risk management was being
managed or executed effectively within
that organization
after the break cnbc tv 18's lata
venkatesh
discusses with eminent jury members on
how india inc
is managing various risk management
processes in organizations
icici lombard and cnbc tv 18 present
india risk management awards
[Music]
the india risk management awards
launched by cnbc tv 18 and icici lombard
has entered its sixth year
and this is one of the most educating
and
enlightening awards given by uh this
combination
of ics lombard and cnbc tv 18 it probes
into
the sophistication that india inc has
reached
in a very important task of risk
management
and to judge you know several hundred
companies
we have with us the creme de la creme of
risk managers
of india inc in this exercise so
participating in the jury round were
ramesh swaminathan uh head of corporate
center at uh
larsen tubular rui bustos head of uh
internal audit at uh reliance industries
vs parsarti the cfo and cio of
mahindra group someone who has looked at
so many verticals within that group
itself
and mr v ramakrishna the cfo of
tcs so as you can see i think between
them uh these
gentlemen account for about 30 percent
of the nifty's market cap itself
so we have the best analyzing whether uh
companies in india inc are coming up to
speed
as far as risk management is concerned
uh the jury deliberations
threw up such a rich set of arguments
and
points that india needs to note mr
parsathi let me start with you
do you think risk management is now
qualitatively a very different
task compared to say 10 years ago how do
you think it's evolved
one of the good things what has happened
is india is
able to look at risks in a much more
refined
manner because it has come into the
journey much later
so we have the experience of what people
have gone through
let's for example do the good part is
that when we did about the governance
aspects the governance risk etcetera and
when udaiko tech committee said that you
know
differentiate between the chairman and
the md so this is
even more evolved than what uh you know
any single country could have so
it's probably one of the best in terms
of risk management
uh from a board point of view yeah uh so
it will take some time to get
implemented but we are very much there
so over a period of time we
evolved we have learned from the world's
best
and we are we are kind of evolving so
the only
risk that we need to kind of be aware of
in this management process
is that we don't make too many matrices
for things that could go wrong because
risk is all about taking not about
avoiding uh
you know being an i.t you deal with a
a whole host of domains would you say
that disruption is a much different
animal today in terms of risk than it
was some time back
business model disruptions obviously are
happening in
across sectors but it is also a huge
opportunity and
the technology itself is a big disrupter
and the technology is helping
organizations navigate this deception
much better that's how i would put it so
disruption is is forgiven and but
what is the lens through which you see
it do you see it as constructive
or do you see it as a as an impediment i
would say that it
one should see it in a positive angle
and what
actually technology is able to do in
that do you think infrastructure risk
we have seen the worst in india or
is this still something we are going
through it's a very tough question to
ask especially in a year
where there's too much of disruption
there's a lot of risk in the
in the air you know across policies
across
across sectors across impact economy the
political risks and so on as well
uh the world itself is in a turmoil when
we get down to in fact the
infrastructure i would think
you've not crossed the hurdle there um
the you know the
the the toss-up is between actual fiscal
um
you know that you actually want to uh
consolidate the fiscal front or would
actually be a little more liberal out
there especially in a different
a very difficult year and that's
something which would be seen in this
year's budget itself
having said that i think there's a lot
of risk associated with the
implementation of infrastructure in
india
and for sure it's something that needs
to be watched out for
re you are in the best position to
analyze where india
inc stands in the pecking order you know
from your
wearing your hat as someone who has seen
several countries
would you say india inc is getting its
head around
risk management or do you think it needs
to do a great deal more to come to
global standards
so i would say two things based on what
i've seen over the last couple of years
india's become a fast follower it's
actually caught up very quickly
and you can see a clear maturity in
terms of the evolution of risk
management practices
across most sectors i think the
challenge comes now in terms of actually
getting us to the next level which is
actually the effectiveness of risk
management processes in terms of how we
deal with
increasingly a much more complex
environment so you're seeing
you've seen two things you're seeing a
lot of uncertainty coming from the world
economy okay geopolitical risks are
going up
as in ways that we had never anticipated
and
india is beginning to having to respond
to economic shocks coming from the
outside world so
that i'm seeing a positive spin because
i'm seeing the sense that it's been able
to respond better than
than some would have anticipated so
that's been good okay
um i think we all struggle with some of
the same challenges that i see
globally as well in the sense that we
are responding okay we are looking
outside so we are becoming much more
open to
risk coming from the outside world in
terms of understanding how that impacts
us
um we've got some good things in terms
of the
um the way the economy is looking at
risk and its understanding of the
external factors coming in
but it's consistency i think how we
become more and more consistent across
multiple sectors is going to be the key
challenge going forward let me come to
this
technology bit uh mr parsavi would you
say that
technology is the biggest risk or
disruptor
or is it something else i think
i made a house of excellence for the
finance and accounts function
and there were two things which were
missing in that when i put up that chart
one was technology and the other was
system and process
and they asked that you know if you
build a house where is the technology
gone and i told them that it's like the
blood
okay it's it's what circulates it goes
in it by itself is neither a disruptor
is is not a
negative or a positive it's it can give
you the opportunity to catapult so
the amazons of this world will thank
technology because they made them
the fastest growing thing in the world
and then there are people
who whose business models are disrupted
because this technology has come
so basically technology is a great
enabler
for the 5 trillion economy for india or
whatever equivalent for the world so
it's a great enabler but you don't see
it as
creating challenges per se for instance
say cyber
or for instance bridging generations
within a company hr challenges the
the key thing is no business will
remain the way it is today all business
models will change
and they will change on two friends one
will be because of climate change
and the second one is because of
experiential commerce not e-commerce
yeah the the world between the physical
and the digital commerce
so the ice which is the companies which
will survive
will be innovative companies is the
theory that i
i float as an individual and why do we
say that is because it's going to
disrupt every economy every company as
we know it
so so is there any company which will
not be disrupted or any industry
my vote is that it will disrupt each
industry so that
that is the that's the fun in
in in going around doing business now is
to embrace that
and work with that environment climate
is fast turning out to be a challenge
can you elaborate that for india in
particular i mean for
say the west or many of the richer
countries after you are between 10 000
and 60 000 per capita income dollars
uh in dollars you have to you know meet
the climate change
in india the uh climate risk
is coming when we are two thousand
dollars per capita correct so i think
the the challenge on india is going to
be
you'll have a the world economy pushing
higher levels of standards and
requirements on to india while india
still
is still evolving its its economy which
some would say is a bit unfair because
other
other countries have had an opportunity
to catch up and put them at
that level of sophistication so i think
india's got a challenge
on the other hand there's a positive
because the technologies that have been
built or put together to respond to
climate was now also now available so
india has the opportunity to leapfrog
through the technologies to actually get
ahead of the climate discussion
but it has some serious challenges
linked to infrastructure for example
which need to be tackled
in order to really address that uh
surrounding christian uh
governance risk is obviously the biggest
risk for
an investor a shareholder how has india
inc
tackled it you think yeah i think if you
read the if you see the noise uh you
have a
mixed uh reaction to that because
uh very once and
once too often you hear of
some instances of where there is
seems to be a failure of governance but
it would be foolish to say that that is
what is symptomatic of across the board
right so but i think the key issue is
the culture
within the organization and uh where
it this is governance cannot be or
adherence to certain norms of behavior
cannot be
only at parts of the organization it has
to flow from the top
the tone at the top and systems and
processes
behaviors and how you are able to
identify
prevent and take steps
for non-recurrence so all the hat
has to in fact that's very bold it's a
very big challenge
it ties into the theme of
this this awards itself
because it goes to the core of how you
manage the
risks around so and governance risk is
also a very important one
well for infrastructure i guess the risk
is more policy risk
do you think india inc has been um
able to get around this i mean it is a
reality and policy risk is not only in
india
the trade war is a policy risk for uh
you know uh
companies located in other parts of the
world in the developed parts of the
world
how do you think this is being
negotiated at a board level
let me tell you that there are
tremendous lessons so far as
infrastructure implementation this part
of the world
firstly i think there is a huge delay of
risk itself so potentially if you look
at in fact some other
um at last count they're close to about
1600 projects which have been delayed
over the last five years so to speak
uh that's actually a quarter a quarter
of in fact the overall projects that are
going through
uh the second risk is relating to
payments itself so if you look at for
example
uh we more often than not get into a lot
of disputes within fact certain
authorities in terms of the payments so
we look at in fact nhai the total
payments due from them is close to about
50 000 crores
with this kind of risk it's very
difficult for the private sector to
carry on
um and that's it's also true that um
there could be a lot of
risks associated with projects being
carried forward uh there are government
changes which take place and potentially
there are risks about certain projects
being cancelled immediately thereafter
even though a lot of work has already
been done
so there is risk associated with the
projects of of various kinds
and it remains to be seen how india inc
and for that matter the government kind
of tackles this
uh mr patadi how would you rate
the way in which indian boards
have been able to capture risk and
manage risk
i think there is a set which we can talk
about
more with more authority than the others
so if you take the top 500 listed
companies
i think there is a set set of norms
which have come they are more evolved
the boards are fairly transparent in
terms of you know getting external
feedback etc i think the progress that
has been very very high
from something which you said audit
committee did everything
to actually having a separate risk
committee
and then having a separate risk
operating committee which reports to the
risk
board subcommittee and then it gets
discussed at every quarter in a board
meeting
so this is very big progress the second
is the
quantum of change in the breadth that
the board i think
they are not comfortable just saying
show me the top two risk or something
they say how have you arrived at the
risk what is the risk mitigation
strategy
can you tell me when the risk is
changing what is fructifying what is
going away
so this this not just you know single
brush but a broad brush
and the breadth is they're saying show
me operating this from strategic resume
you know as they call temples yeah so
this is a new term that i learned first
a year back when they put up this temple
so it's it's
all the kind of other environment and
other is that we have
they're they're aware about the board
risks they're about about the management
risk they're about at the
operating risk so i think it's evolved a
lot
salaam krishna mr patstos and remy
swaminathan thank you very much
for joining me in this conversation
icici lombard
and cnbc tv 18 present india risk
management awards
focus innovate
enable